so now that we've learned the absolute trick and the square trick,
我们已经学习了绝对值巧和平方技巧
and how they're used in linear regression,
以及怎样在线性回归问题中使用这些技巧
we still want to have some intuition on how these things get figured out.
但我们还想对这些技巧有个直觉理解
These tricks still seem a little too magical,
这些技巧真是太神奇了
and we'd like to find their origin so let's do this in a much more formal way.
我们想探索一下它们的本质 开始吧
Let's say we have our points on our plan is to develop an algorithm which
假设我们想开发一个算法
will find the line that best fits this set of points.
来为一组点找到一条最佳拟合的线
And the algorithm works like this,
算法的工作步骤如下
first it will draw a random line,
首先 随机画条直线
and it'll calculate the error.
计算它的误差
The error is some measure of how far the points are from the line,
这个误差表示点到直线的距离
in this drawing it looks like it's the sum of these distances but it could
本图中 距离的度量方法是点到直线的垂直距离之和  (或纵坐标绝对值误差)
be any measure that tells us how far we are from the points.
你也可以使用其他度量方法  (例如 水平距离)
Now we're going to move the line around and see if we can decrease this error.
现在我们移动一下这条线 看误差会不会减小
We move in this direction and we see that
沿这个方向移动线
the error kind of increases so that's not the way to go.
可以看到误差在增加 所以不是这个方向
So we move in the other direction and see that the error decreased,
再沿另一个方向移动线  现在误差减少了
so we pick this one and stay there.
所以我们选这个方向
Now we'll repeat the process many times over and over every time
重复这个过程
descending the error a bit until we get to the perfect line.
一点点减少误差 直到找到误差最小的那条线
So to minimize this error,
我们将用梯度下降算法
we're going to use something called gradient descent.
来最小化误差
So let me talk a bit about gradient descent,
现在开始介绍梯度下降
the way it works is we're standing here on top of a mountain.
梯度下降的工作方式就像是下山
This is called Mt rainierror as it measures how big our error is,
这座山叫雷尼尔山 误差就象这座山
and wanted descend from this mountain in order to
我们想下山
descend from this mountain we need to minimize our height.
要下山 我们需要减少高度
And on the left, we have a problem of fitting the line to the data,
在右侧 我们要用一条直线来拟合这些数据点
which we can do by minimizing the error or the distance from the line to the points.
我们通过一点点减少误差来让这条直线贴近这些点
So descending from the mountain is equivalent to getting the line closer to the points.
因此下山等价于线性拟合问题
Now, if we wanted to descend from
如果我们想下山
the mountain we would look at the directions where we can walk
我们就要先找下山的路
down and find the one that makes us descend the most.
要选择一个下山最快的方向
And let's say this is the direction,
假设选这个方向
so we descend a bit in this direction,
我们沿这个方向下降一点
this is equivalent to getting the line a little bit closer to the points.
这等价于让这条线靠近这些点一点
So now our height is smaller because we're closer to
现在我们的高度降了一点
the points since our distance to them is smaller.
同样这条线也更靠近这些点了
And again and again we look at what makes us descend the most
不断重复这个过程  寻找下山最快的方向
from the mountain and let's say we get here.
假如说我们到达这儿
Now we're at a point where we're descended from the mountain and on
现在我们到达山底
the right we found the line that is very close to our points.
在右图 我们也找到了那条最佳拟合线
Thus, we've solved our problem and that is gradient descent.
这就是梯度下降
In a more mathematical way what happens is the following,
现在我们再用数学语言来描叙一下梯度下降
we have a plot and here's a plot in two dimensions
这是一个二维图像
allowing a reality that plot will be in higher dimensions.
也可以扩展到更高维的情况
We have our weights on the x-axis and our error on the y-axis.
X轴表示权重  Y轴表示误差
And we have an error function that looks like this,
这个是误差函数
we're standing over here and the way to descend is to actually take
开始时我们站在这里
the derivative or gradient of the error function with respect to the weights.
这里下山的方法就是计算误差函数关于每个权重的梯度
This gradient is going to point to a direction where the function increases the most.
梯度方向总是指向误差函数增大最多的方向
Therefore, the negative of this gradient is going to point
而逆梯度方向则指向
down in the direction where the function decreases the most.
误差函数减少最多的方向
So what we do is we take a step in the direction of the negative of that gradient,
因此我们沿逆梯度方向走一步
this means we are taking our weights wi and changing them to
这一步表示用原权重 wi减去
wi minus the derivative of the error with respect to wi.
误差相对于权重 wi的梯度
In real life we'll be multiplying this derivative by
实际上还要用学习速率 乘以误差的梯度
the learning rate since we want to make small steps.
因为我们控制步长大小
This means the error function is decreasing and we're closer to the minimum.
这意味着误差函数不断减小  我们快接近最小值了
If we do this several times we get to
重复上述过程
either a minimum or a pretty good value where the error is small.
就可以得到误差最小或很好的值
Once we get to the point that we've reached
一旦我们到这个点
a pretty good solution for our linear regression problem,
我们就找到了线性回归问题的一个很好的解决方案
and that's what gradient descent is all about
这就是梯度下降算法